<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Cong T. Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://nctung4.github.io/Project_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Cong T. Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nctung4.github.io/Project_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Car Price Prediction</title>
      <link>https://nctung4.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nctung4.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Link to GitHub repository.
Car Price Prediction This project is a end-to-end data science project, from data collecting, to making it into production.
Project Overview  Created a tool that estimates car prices (RMSE:~293K, MAE:~293K HUF) to help people negotiate or estimate the specific price, when they want to either buy or sell a car. Used web scraping techniques to get the data from hasznaltauto.hu. (hungarian car trading website) Applied several data cleaning and feature engineering techniques, such as handling missing data or feature scaling Optimized multiple linear regression, support vector regression, random forest regression, and xgboost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Customer Segmentation and Classification</title>
      <link>https://nctung4.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nctung4.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Link to GitHub repository.
The focus of this project is on cluster analysis, and classification modeling on a customer database.
Project Summary  Used the k-Means algorithm on the cleaned dataset for creating the clusters. Decided the optimal number of clusters with the elbow method and silhouette scores. Optimized several classification models with grid search. (KNN, SVC, Decision Tree, Random Forest, XGBoost, Logistic Regression etc.) I applied a voting classifier ensemble technique, to have the most accurate result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Face Mask Detection</title>
      <link>https://nctung4.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nctung4.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Link to GitHub repository.
Overview:  It is a real-time face mask detection project, developed in python, using Deep Learning and OpenCV. I used the transfer learning technique. (MobileNetV2 architecture) Used several preprocessing technique, such as one-hot encoding the labels, or constructing the training image for data augmentation. The final model performs absolutely amazing, with almost a 100% accuracy.  Resources used: Python Version: 3.8.5
Packages: numpy, opencv-python, tensorflow, matplotlib, sickit-learn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Flu Time Series Forecast</title>
      <link>https://nctung4.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nctung4.github.io/Project_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Flu Time Series Forecasting This is a time series forecasting project. I wanted to make a model which can be applied to flu time series forecasting. I downloaded the data from WHO public database. The data is ranging from 2010.01.01 to 2020.06.30, and it is focused on the European WHO region. It is a weekly data. I created the models in Rstudio, and for deep learning models (LSTM) I used python.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
